Revenge Mystery Danger Ambush
Breakheart Pass is a thriller, western, mystery film directed by Tom Gries.
At the height of the frontier era, a train races through the Rocky
Mountains on a classified mission to a remote army post.
But one by one the passengers are being murdered, and their only hope is the
mysterious John Deakin, who's being transported to face trial for murder.
John Deakin, played by Charles Bronson.
Deputy U.S. Marshal Nathan Pearce, played by Ben Johnson.
Gov. Richard Fairchild, played by Richard Crenna.
Marica Scoville, played by Jill Ireland.
Frank O'Brien, played by Charles Durning.
Major Claremont, played by Ed Lauter.
Breakheart Pass is a 1975 American Western film that stars Charles
Bronson, Ben Johnson, Richard Crenna, and Jill Ireland.
Based on the 1974 novel of the same title by Scottish author Alistair
MacLean (1922–1987), it was filmed in north-central Idaho.
The film explores themes of governor, army, prisoner, u.s. marshal, train.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.